<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Hadi&#39;s Cool Blog</title>
    <link>https://hadi-el-hajj.github.io/blog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Hadi&#39;s Cool Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 11:09:23 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hadi-el-hajj.github.io/blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Unity</title>
      <link>https://hadi-el-hajj.github.io/blog/posts/setting_up_unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 11:09:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hadi-el-hajj.github.io/blog/posts/setting_up_unity/</guid>
      <description>Setting Unity was not very hard. Nonetheless, it is great to have a simple guide at your disposition upon installation so you can go faster. I will lay it out for you !
REMARK : I love using Linux, but unfortunately Unity is not fully supported there yet. So if you are indeed using the Linux OS, I would recommend you use windows or mac instead. Nonetheless, keep checking the unity website for updates, the launch of the Linux supported version should be released in 2021 !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up my Blog</title>
      <link>https://hadi-el-hajj.github.io/blog/posts/setting_up_the_blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 15:32:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hadi-el-hajj.github.io/blog/posts/setting_up_the_blog/</guid>
      <description>Installing Hugo ! Installing Hugo was not hard since I was using Linux. This said, I did encounter some difficulties with version updates. I wanted at first to use Introduction, but the theme needed higher versions of HUgo. After figuring out how to upgrade the distribution I had (see images below of the problem as mentioned on Stack Overflow) (a simple sudo apt&amp;hellip; did not work, installing hugo through Ubuntu Software neither) and getting Introduction to build, I had another issue which is cited on the theme&amp;rsquo;s Github page, but I was already a bit off the theme and just wanted to choose a new one at this stage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The_ultimate_display</title>
      <link>https://hadi-el-hajj.github.io/blog/posts/the_ultimate_display/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 14:12:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hadi-el-hajj.github.io/blog/posts/the_ultimate_display/</guid>
      <description>Review of Ivan Sutherland&amp;rsquo;s THE ULTIMATE DISPLAY This blog post is intended to try and analyze how Sutherland&amp;rsquo;s Ultimate Display fits into the Reality-Virtuality Continuum of Milgram. First, let me import the representation of the RV continuum:
In the light of this refresher, it feels that Sutherland&amp;rsquo;s ultimate display traces the lines between a Real Environment and a Virtual Environment, and thus is surrounding the continuum.
In fact, Sutherland talks extensively about the relashionship between virtual environments and real environments, and the fact that virtual environments can make us apprehend more and more what can and cannot happen in the real world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyper-Reality by Keiichi Matsuda</title>
      <link>https://hadi-el-hajj.github.io/blog/posts/session-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 11:09:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hadi-el-hajj.github.io/blog/posts/session-1/</guid>
      <description>Review of the HYper-Reality video ! Hyper reality presents multiple scenarios where the user is subjected to potential dangers, from which we can cite both being hacked and being bombarbed by waves and waves of commercials. This said, it is too short to englobe all the possibility of dangers, which include:
  being trolled on the internet. Imagine posting a social media post and receiving such criticism that you become an internet meme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome !</title>
      <link>https://hadi-el-hajj.github.io/blog/posts/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:40:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hadi-el-hajj.github.io/blog/posts/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Hello There ! Awesome to see you !
Welcome to my personal website where I will be showcasing some of the projects I worked on to you !
Feel free to read my posts, and come back to me for feedback anytime !
Cheers, Hadi</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
